PETER FORTUNA

Brooklyn, New York | (309) 713-9875 | peter.j.fortuna@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | Github

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Versatile software engineer with experience in application development using React, cloud infrastructure and database management in AWS and GCP, and data science in Python. Right now, I'm focused on designing and developing Al-powered applications and innovative user experiences.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

M.S. in Computer Science | Arizona State University | December 2024

B.S. in Mathematics | Brigham Young University | Provo, Utah | June 2022

AWS Certified Solutions Architect | Amazon Web Service | December 2023

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, SQL **Platforms:** AWS, GCP, React, React Native

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern | Paramount | New York, New York | June 2024 - August 2024

- Explored ways to use LLMs and RAG on Paramount's advertising metadata.
- Created a React dashboard POC for our data ingestion process.

Data Engineer | DriveWealth | Jersey City, New Jersey | September 2022 - January 2023

- Developed a Python library to process encoded BOE and OUCH protocol financial messages, enabling ETL processing of new stock market transactions.
- Implemented an Azure SQL-based solution to regularly analyze gigabytes of stock market data, effectively mitigating the firm's compliance risk.

Al Research Assistant | BYU | Provo, Utah | January 2020 - April 2022

- Increased team productivity 300% by automating the training process for our AI text extraction project, saving months of work for the five-person team.
- Utilized advanced machine learning and statistical algorithms to identify trends in both structured and unstructured social science datasets.

Data Analyst Intern | CUNA Mutual Group | Madison, Wisconsin | June 2021 - August 2021

- Conducted interviews with cybersecurity experts and presented findings to a panel of stakeholders.
- Decreased the data processing times of a monthly insurance forecast over 80% by automating a manual process using SQL queries and procedural programming.

PROJECTS

Generative AI Mad Libs Application | October 2024 - December 2024

- Built a full stack application to create and share AI generated Mad Libs.
- The front end is React and the backend uses AWS Lambda, S3, and DynamoDB
- Check it out at snaplibs.com

OUCH Financial Message Parser | February 2023 - March 2023

- Published a Python library to decode trading messages on the open-source repository PyPI.
- See project: <u>GitHub OUCH Financial Message Parser</u>